我们现在将更多地讨论如何访问矩阵的元素
We are going to talk now a little bit more about how we access the elements of the matrix
它表示来自MATLAB环境内部的图像。而我们将会这样做
which represents an image from inside the MATLAB environment. And we are going to do
这是从命令行工具交互式地进行的。我们将首先加载一个图像
this interactively from the command line tool. We will start by loading an image, one that
我们之前见过几次。这是蒙娜丽莎的形象，有PNG扩展，和
we have seen a few times before. It is the Mona Lisa image, has a PNG extension, and
我们要将它从颜色转换为灰度，因为我们还没有真正谈过
we are going to convert it from colour to grey scale because we have not really talked
关于颜色呢。我们已将图像加载到工作区中，我可以使用工具箱
about colour yet. And we have loaded the image into our workspace, and I can use the toolbox
命令，告诉我们关于那个特定图像的更多信息。
command about, to tell us a bit more about that particular image.
它告诉我们图像变量的类型为uint8，宽度为700像素
It tells us that the image variable is of the type uint8, that it is 700 pixels wide
和677像素高，占用470千字节的内存。
and 677 pixels tall, and occupies 470 kilobytes of memory.
我现在要做的是显示图像，这些命令应该很漂亮
What I am going to do now is to display the image and again these commands should be pretty
你很熟悉还有蒙娜丽莎的形象。正如我们之前讨论的那样，我们可以
familiar to you. And there is the Mona Lisa image. And as we discussed before, we can
四处移动，我们可以点击像素，我们可以查看灰度值。我们可以点击
move around, we can click pixels and we can look at the grey scale value. And we can click
那里有一个像素，在她的眼睛中间。它的价值相当低。就是这样
a pixel there, in the middle of her eye. And it has got quite a low value. It is in that
她眼睛的黑暗部分。现在，我们直接从中访问该变量
dark part of her eye. Now, we access that variable directly from
在MATLAB环境中，我将选择垂直的行坐标
the MATLAB environment, and I am going to choose the row coordinate which is the vertical
图像中的坐标，即194，以及作为水平坐标的列坐标
coordinate in the image, that is 194 and the column coordinate which is a horizontal coordinate
那么请记住我们之前谈过这个问题：我们必须改变坐标
276. So remember we talked about this before: we have to reverse the coordinates from the
u，v符号，水平和垂直坐标系统到MATLAB的行和列索引
u,v notation, horizontal and vertical coordinate system to MATLAB’s row and column index
对于矩阵，我们看到相同的值26，即低灰度值，暗
for matrices, and there we see that same value, 26, that is a low grey scale value, a dark
表示她眼中像素强度的值。
value which represents the intensity of that pixel within her eye.
我们用MATLAB做的另一件事是不仅可以访问单个像素，而且实际上可以访问
Another thing we can do with MATLAB is to access not just a single pixel, but in fact
一块像素，我们使用MATLAB的冒号运算符。所以让我们选择所有行
a block of pixels, and we do that using MATLAB’s colon operator. So let’s choose all rows
180到210之间，所有列从260开始，最多290.当我点击进入时，我们是
between 180 and 210, and all columns starting at 260, up to 290. When I hit enter, we are
将看到大量像素值滚动过去。所以我可以回头看看
going to see a large number of pixel values scroll past. So I can roll back up and look
他们都在那里。所以它已经返回，在这种情况下是一个矩阵。
at all of them there. So it has returned, in this case a matrix.
一个小矩阵;原始图像的子矩阵。
A small matrix; a sub-matrix of the original image.
我们实际上将它放入工作空间变量中，我将通过返回来实现
Let’s actually put that into a workspace variable, and I will do that by coming back
并编辑该命令行。我们走了。所以我创建了一个新变量
and editing that command line. There we go. So I have created a new variable
工作空间称为im2，它是一个31x31像素的图像。我可以显示出来。和我们
workspace called im2 and it is a 31 by 31 pixel image. And I can display that. And we
看一个图像，这实际上是蒙娜丽莎的眼睛。
see an image, which is actually the eye of the Mona Lisa.
这次不是选择一个像素块，而是选择一行像素。
This time instead of selecting a block of pixels, I am going to choose a line of pixels.
我将把结果放入一个名为lin的变量中，这样就可以了
I am going to do that by putting the result into a variable called lin, and this is the
包含原始图像的MATLAB变量。我将选择第190行和所有
MATLAB variable that contains the original image. I am going to select row 190 and all
在260和290之间的列中的像素。在这里，它们是像素值
pixels in columns between 260 and 290. And here they are, these are the pixel values
沿着蒙娜丽莎图像的一个短水平段。我可以用它来描绘。
along a short horizontal segment of the Mona Lisa image. And I can plot that.
在这里我们看到强度曲线。开始很轻，从中间落下
And here we see an intensity profile. Starts off quite light, falls down the middle as
我们经历了蒙娜丽莎眼中的黑暗部分，然后去了更大的灰度值
we go through the dark part of the Mona Lisa’s eye, and then go to larger greyscale values
当我们回到构成她脸部的像素时。
as we move back onto the pixels that comprise her face.
我们可以使用冒号运算符执行许多其他有趣且有用的技巧。
There are a number of other interesting and useful tricks we can do with a colon operator.
我要创建另一个输出图像。这次我打算把它称为im3和什么
I am going to create another output image. This time I am going to call it im3 and what
我要做的是再次选择蒙娜丽莎的形象，我将选择所有的
I am going to do is select again the Mona Lisa image and I am going to choose all the
行从1开始以4为步骤结束，这是一个特殊的MATLAB变量，代表
rows starting at 1 in steps of 4 up to end, which is a special MATLAB variable which represents
矩阵中最大的行号。并从中开始再次选择所有列
the largest row number in the matrix. And select all the columns again, starting at
1步骤4到最大列号并创建一个名为的新工作空间变量
1 in steps of 4 up to the largest column number and create a new workspace variable called
im3，我将显示该图像。开始了。
im3 and I am going to display that image. Here we go.
我们现在可以看到的是，这张图片的分辨率要低得多，我们可以看到
And what we can see now is that this image has much lower resolution, we can see the
像素的块状，我们可以看到那里的水平和垂直方向
blockiness of the pixels, we can see in the horizontal and vertical directions that there
这个图像中的像素远远少于原始像素，这是因为什么
are far fewer pixels in this image than there are in the original and that is because what
我们所做的是从水平方向和中间每四个像素中选择一个
we have done is chosen every fourth pixel from both the horizontal direction and in
垂直方向。我们降低了图像的分辨率。所以这很快
the vertical direction. We have reduced the resolution of the image. So that is a quick
使用冒号运算符可以使用MATLAB。
trick you can do with MATLAB, using the colon operator.
关于结肠操作符的最后一点是有用的-我要创建
The final thing that is useful to know about the colon operator—I am going to create
又一个图像，这次我要做的是我要选择行
yet another image, and this time what I am going to do is I am going to choose the rows
从最后开始，从最大可能的行号开始，向下步进-1，
starting at end, starting at the biggest possible row number, going in steps of -1 working downwards,
直到我进入第1行，然后我将从一个选择所有列
until I get to row 1, and then I am going to choose all of the columns from one up to
结束。你可以想象这是怎么回事
end. You can probably imagine what this is going
去做。我们去了-我们已经翻了Mona
to do. And there we go—we have flipped the Mona
丽莎颠倒了。最后一个快速提示是我们输入的最后一个命令;我们实际上可以
Lisa upside down. One final quick tip is that the last command that we typed; we can actually
让它更简洁一点。我们需要写出我们说所有列的最后一部分
make it a bit more concise. We need to write that last part where we say all of the columns
从1到结束，我们可以非常简单地将其写成冒号。所以无论你有什么
from 1 to end, we can write that down very simply just as colon. So where ever you have
冒号表示矩阵的列或行，表示全部。我们可以将其视为外卡运营商。
colon to represent a column or row of a matrix, it means all. We can think of it as a wild card operator.